Morgane Fortin

Data scientist

33 years, French citizen

🗥 Dublin, Ireland

ganetin@gmail.com

+33 6 70 59 82 21

users.camk.edu.pl/fortin

Technical Skills —

Linux

Python

Fortran

Mathematica

C/C++

Git

HTML and CSS

Soft Skills -

- Independent thinker
- Responsible & determined
- Excellent communicator
- Team builder & project initiator
- ₩ell-organized and disciplined

Languages -



Personal interests

- Sailing for 20+ years
- Cinema, literature, opera
- Video games
- Genealogy
- Amateur crypto investor
- First aid diploma

Personal Statement

Former astrophysicist turned data scientist bringing 11 years of analytical research experience and dynamism to an organization seeking innovative data-oriented solutions. My adaptability and strong motivation allow me to quickly learn new skills and tools, both in a team and independently. My solid background in problem-solving, programming, and data visualisation, together with my ability to communicate complex ideas across diverse audiences in uncomplicated terms, will be an asset to any organisation.

Education

Mar. 2019

	Physics and Cosmology
	Probability, Statistics and Machine Learning
2012	PhD in Astronomy and Astrophysics Warsaw (PL) & Paris (FR)
	Polish Academy of Sciences & Paris Observatory with highest honors; joint Polish & French Ph.D. programme
2009	MSc in Astrophysics Paris (FR)
	Pierre and Marie Curie University, Ecole Normale Supérieure & Paris Observatory – with honors

Data Science School in (Astro-)Particle

Work Experience

Aug. – Sept. 2020 Data Scientist - S2DS Fellow

Successfully delivered team project for SEGRO PLC (Europe's largest investor in industrial Real Estate) to optimise client's portfolio through Manipulation & Visualization of Geospatial Data (GeoPandas, Folium, Shapely), Web-scraping, Geocoding and extensive use of

APIs.

2014 – Sept. 2020 Assistant Professor (Nuclear Astrophysics) Warsaw (PL)

Extensive use of Python (NumPy, Matplotlib, SciPy, ...), Data Visualisation and Machine-Learning techniques (linear regression, confidence intervals, correlations, calibration and optimisation of multi-parameter models) on a cluster

Published 30+ articles in renowned international journals, gave 5+ invited talks, 20+ seminars/presentations around the world, and lectures in Physics at all levels across Europe.

Key contributor to winning grants (\in 1.2M in total).

Conceived and organised 3 international conferences (50-250 participants each).

Member of 3 European networks & 3 Space Mission projects.

Contributed to popularisation of astronomy (books, movies, interviews, translations).

Mentored female students in STEM from around the world.

2016 - Sept. 2020 Visiting Researcher

Coimbra (PT)

Braga (PT)

Completed 10+ projects including machine-learning aspects, acting as a bridge between Astrophysics and Nuclear Physics.

2012 – 2014 Postdoctoral Researcher

Rome (IT)

Worked as an independent researcher building contacts around the world.

Expanded my expertise from Astrophysics to include Nuclear Physics.